Finding Aid for Professional Theatre Program (University of Michigan) records, 1962-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Professional Theatre Program (University of Michigan) records
1962-1985
University of Michigan. Professional Theatre Program.
87273 Bimu F65 2
Papers, 1962-1985 of the Professional Theatre Program at the University of Michigan. Contain executive director's file, including correspondence, newspaper clippings and related theatrical material of Robert C. Schnitzer, and publicity files of clippings and press releases concerning play productions and other programs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
28 linear feet
The records were received in several acquisitions (donors nos. 4156, 5488 and 5361 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
Established in 1961, the Professional Theatre Program was designed to bring outstanding professional theater to the university community. Its first director, Robert Schnitzer, who served from 1962 to 1973, was also a member of the faculty, and the program was integrated with the theater curriculum through a graduate student program.
The Professional Theatre Program records include executive director's files (1962-1972), Professional Theatre Program Fellows Tour files (1966-1972), publicity files (1962-1985, films and photographs. Planning for the Power Center and the early years of its operation are also covered.
Visual materials includes films of classical drama programs for schools, and photos of PTP directors. Recordings consist of uncompiled sound clips, background music, and sound effects for a film entitled "Conjuror."
Subjects:
Drama.; Theater--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Speech.; University of Michigan--Dramatics.Dramatics.; University of Michigan. Professional Theatre Program.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Cisney, Marcella.; Schnitzer, Robert C., 1906-; Theatrical productions.; University of Michigan. Professional Theatre Program.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
University of Michigan. Professional Theatre Program.
Contributors:
Schnitzer, Robert C., 1906-
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Sound recordings.
- Executive Director's Files, 1962-1972
  - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - (cont.), 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - (cont.), 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - (cont.), 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - (cont.), 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - (cont.), 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - (cont.), 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 7)
  - (cont.), 1966-1967 (Box 8)
  - (cont.), 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - (cont.), 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - (cont.), 1968-1969 (Box 11)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - (cont.), 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 14)
- Professional Theatre Program Fellows Tour, 1966-1972
  - 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 16)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 16)
- Publicity File, 1962-1972
  - 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - (cont.), 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - (cont.), 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - (cont.), 1966-1967 (Box 20)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 20)
  - (cont.), 1967-1968 (Box 21)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 21)
  - (cont.), 1968-1969 (Box 22)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - (cont.), 1969-1970 (Box 23)
  - 1969-1970(cont.) (Box 24)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 24)
  - (cont.), 1970-1971 (Box 25)
  - (cont.), 1970-1971 (Box 26)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 27)
- Programs
  - Programs for PTP Presentations to, 1985 (Box 27)
- Films
  - "Magic of the Stage,"a program of classic drama for schools, 1969; 16mm b & w sound approximately 30 minutes (Box 28)
  - "Mask of Imagination," a program of classic drama for schools, 1971; 16mm b & w sound approximately 30 minutes (Box 28)
  - "Conjuror," uncompiled clips, 3 reels 16mm b & w sound (Box 28)
- Photographs
  - Marcella Cisney, Robert Schnitzer and others, 1 envelopes (Box 28)
- Sound Recordings
  - "Conjuror," uncompiled sound clips, background music and sound effects, 3 reels 7.5 ips. reel-to-reel (Box 28)